BULYGIN MAKSIM

+7(922)202-26-02 \$\display \text{Saint-Petersburg, Russia \$\display \text{max.buligin@gmail.com}}

⊘BulyginMaksim ⋄ **○**BulyginMaksim ⋄ **in**bulyginmaksim

SUMMARY

Passionate Machine Learning Engineer with over 2 years of experience, working at VK and ITMO master & YSDA student. Accomplished in developing ETL pipelines and building efficient Machine Learning algorithms. Enthusiastic about developing Machine Learning algorithms and processing Big Data.

EXPERIENCE

VK, Machine Learning Engineer (RecSys)

January 2023 - Present

• Develope ETL pipelines processing Big Data on Spark using Scala

Yandex, Machine Learning Engineer (anti-fraud)

June 2021 – January 2023

- Ensured the migration of the anti-fraud service to the cloud: migrated real-time anti-fraud rules to streaming processing and batch anti-fraud rules to dbt from the Yandex infrastructure to Azure
- \bullet Developed heuristic and advanced anti-fraud rules: increased the number of anti-fraud rules by 20%, increased the recall of anti-fraud rules by 12%
- Built anti-fraud infrastructure: accelerated main anti-fraud microservice operation time by 10 times and developed various tools for the needs of the anti-fraud analytics group
- Conducted ad-hoc analytics with researches for new fraud signals and detection of suspicious traffic: interacted with the anti-fraud analytics group and performed analytical tasks
- Designed alerts and monitorings infrastructure for the anti-fraud analytics group: developed a microservice supporting convinient way of creating alerts and monitorings by anti-fraud analysts

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

LanguagesPython, SQL, Scala, C++, Java, Wolfram MathematicaFrameworksML Stack (pandas, numpy, sklearn, etc), Spark, TorchToolsGit, Docker, Linux, AirFlow, dbt, Databricks, Azure

EDUCATION

ITMO University 2022 – Present

• Master's degree in Computer Science, joint Master's program of ITMO University and Yandex, GPA 5.0/5.0

Saint-Petersburg State University of Economics

2018 - 2022

• Bachelor's degree in Economics, specialized in mathematical methods in Economics, GPA 5.0/5.0

ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

Yandex School of Data Analysis, Moscow

2022 - Present

Computer Science Center, Saint-Petersburg

2020 - 2022

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Winner of hackathon "Applied AI Challenge: Oil and Gas Industry", 2022
- Winner of Open International Internet Olympiad in the discipline "Mathematics", 2021
- Scholarship holder of Alfa-Bank, Viking Bank, Gazprombank, Gazprom and the Government of Saint-Petersburg